<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Weijiang Xiong</title>
    <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain Reaction</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/chain-reaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/chain-reaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018 Open-Source Hardware and Programming, I organized a mechanical experiment as the TA lead.
This module consist of 5 electro-mechanical sub-modules.
In this class, students need to assemble the mechanical parts of the module, and program an Arduino to control the motion of it.
Every five modules could be connected in a row to guide the motion of an orb.
You can find the demonstration video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X094g3h9elY&amp;amp;t=0s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Course</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/deep-learning-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/deep-learning-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Deep Learning course in Tongji University (2019 FALL) contains the following contents:
- Machine learning basics: Linear regression/classification, Logistic regression for multi-class Classification problems.
- Artificial Neural Networks: Fully-Connected Neural Networks, Convolutional Neural Networks, Recurrent Neural Networks.
- Applications of Deep Learning: Image Classification, Transfer Learning, Style Transfer, Object Detection, Segmentation, GAN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assignments include:
Linear Regression with Numpy
Logistic Regression with Numpy
Multi-class Logistic Regression with Numpy
A 2-layer Fully-Connected Neural Networks with Numpy
Image Classification with Pytorch
Style Transfer with VGG19 and Pytorch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find my solutions &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Weijiang-Xiong/DLcourse&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Pendulum</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/inverted-pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/inverted-pendulum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An inverted pendulum is a pendulum that has its center of mass above its pivot point.
It is unstable and without additional help will fall over.
It can be suspended stably in this inverted position by using a control system to monitor the angle of the pole and move the pivot point horizontally back under the center of mass when it starts to fall over, keeping it balanced.
The inverted pendulum is a classic problem in dynamics and control theory and is used as a benchmark for testing control strategies.
In the project for Control Engineering, I designed a PID controller for a first order inverted pendulum, and compared its performance with the LQR controller.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn DL with Pytorch</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/learn-pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/learn-pytorch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pytorch is the most popular deep learning framework in academic works.
I got to know it through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Weijiang-Xiong/DLcourse&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;deep learning course&lt;/a&gt; in Tongji, the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://pytorch.org/tutorials/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and the online course &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SKq-pmkekTk&amp;amp;list=PLlMkM4tgfjnJ3I-dbhO9JTw7gNty6o_2m&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PyTorchZeroToAll&lt;/a&gt;.
You can see some of my practice &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Weijiang-Xiong/pyIntro/tree/master/Pytorch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEB in PUMA</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/peb-puma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/peb-puma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PACE is an international collaborative competition.
We took part in the PACE 2018 Forum with excellent team mate from TU Darmstadt and Tu Turin.
In the PUMA project, our intelligent Portable Electrical Bicycle (PEB) aimed to improve the short-range transportation in urban life and I built the driving control module for it.
To further endow PEB with the ability to perceive the visual world, I embedded an object detector based on YOLO and Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply Station</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/supply-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:58:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/project/supply-station/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Superpower Robot Team, I took the responsibility of the mechanical design of the supply station.
My team participated in RoboMaster 2017, a robot tactical combat competition, and we won the second prize in Eastern China Sector.
The supply station need to collect bullet balls from a &amp;ldquo;tube&amp;rdquo;, store them and distribute them to fellow robots.
It serves as the foundation of the whole match and means a lot.
Generally, it consist of 3 layers, which are collecting, storing and distributing layers from top to bottom.
The supply station is a flexible platform, which I designed intentionally in case of any changes.
It worked steadily during the competition in Eastern China Sector and efficiently supported the fight of my team.
And in the qualifying games for National Competition, the regulations on supply station had a little modification, the number of bullet balls provided each in each game had been significantly increased.
As a result, we could have enough bullets to load fellow robots several times!
I designed a more efficient and robust triggering facility to adapt to that change.
Besides, I reformed the collecting layer by adding a counting function, so that we could precisely distribute bullets to our fighters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
