<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Weijiang Xiong</title>
    <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 21:00:43 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 21:00:43 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://weijiang-xiong.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Weijiang Xiong (熊伟江) is a second-year robotics master student at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aalto.fi/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aalto University&lt;/a&gt;. He is now working on his master thesis as a research intern at Nokia Technologies. His is broadly interested in Artificial Intelligence, but with a focus on the application of visual perception and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vision4robotics.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vision4Robotics Group&lt;/a&gt; at Tongji University, he began his academic exploration from Visual Object Tracking for UAV. He then explored Bayesian Deep Learning methods in his summer project at &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.cs.aalto.fi/pml/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aalto PML Group&lt;/a&gt;, and applied Normalizing Flows to model the probabilistic distribution of the aleatoric uncertainties for neural networks. During his exchange at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epfl.ch/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EPFL&lt;/a&gt;, he completed a project at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/vita/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VITA Lab&lt;/a&gt;, where he utilized body poses as an intermediate representation to recognize pedestrian’s actions. For his thesis, he is studying self-/semi-supervised methods for object detection in aerial images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His academic path has made him realize the gap between academic state-of-the-art and down-to-the-ground applications, and stimulated his eager for gaining insights into reliable AI applications in the field. His latest resume could be found &lt;a href=&#34;files/Resume_Weijiang_Xiong.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and here are the combined &lt;a href=&#34;files/slides.pptx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; for his past research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
